
Q1. What is high level and low level language?
>> High level language can easily be understood or interpreted by programmers. It is the language in which we code, eg Python Java etc. Low level language is undeerstood by the computer.

Q2. What is a compiler?
>> The compiler converts the source code into the object code which is understood by the machine.

Q3. What is the difference between a code and a program?
>>COding simply means converting human language into machine commands through an intermediary coding language, whereas proProgramming means the process of development of a fully functioning software solution.
A coder requires a basic knowledge of a programming language, its syntax, and keywords.
A programmer should be a skilled individual with substantial experience in creating algorithms, modelling a problem, data processing, and project management.

Q4. How is a program stored in a RAM?

Q5. How is memory allocatted?

Q6. How is memory deleted?

Q7. How does Python know about the data type assigned?
>> Python knows about the data type by the value assigend to it. For instance, "" suggests that the datatype is a strnig.

Q8. How to print memory?
>> print(id())

Q9. Why is memory representation different for same memory in complex numbers?

Q10. Why makes Java a platform independent language unlike other languages?
>> A compiler converts high level language into a code which can directly be executed by the CPU, or it may be converted into a intermediate representation that is read by a virtual machine. In case of Java, the intermediate representation is the Java Byte Code and the virtual machine is JVM. Now, every system has its own JVM, different for all, which gets installed automatically and is able to read Java Byte Code. So, though Java is platform independent, JVM still depends on the platform. This make Java not a completely platform independent language.
In Languages like C, the compiler generates a .exe file whose execution depends on the type of OS used.
So, Java is platform independent but it is machine dependant.

Q11. C vs C++ vs Java vs Python?
>> i.Compiled languages are translated into machine code before they are executed, while interpreted languages are translated into machine code at runtime by an interpreter. Pyhton is interpreted language while rest are compiled language.
ii.Operator Overloading?
iii.Pythohn and Java are platform independent. Rest are dependant.
iv.Syntax rules are strictly followed but in python it may not be necessary to put semicolon.
v.Compiling Speed: C=C++>Java>Python
vi.Libraries contain pre written code that can be used to performr some tasks. Python>Java>C,C++.
vii. Threads?

Q12. What is IDE?
Integrated development environment enable to combine the various aspects of writing a computer program all in one place like editing source code, building executables, and debugging. It also provides with features such as syntax highlighting and autocomplete etc.


